# 江苏·高邮
Gaoyou, Jiangsu
# 雪鱼现在在扬州高邮 今天的天气真的是特别好
Xueyu is now in Gaoyou, Yangzhou. Today’s weather is really good.
# 待会呢 我要去吃一碗这边比较特色的早餐 阳春面
I will have a bowl of special breakfast called Yangchun noodles later
# 阳春面可不是说是高邮独有的
Yangchun noodles are not unique in Gaoyou
# 像扬州 上海 也是比较常见的
Which are pretty common in Yangzhou, Shanghai too
# 那高邮的阳春面做的这么出名
Gaoyou’s Yangchun noodles are so famous
# 在做法和味道上 肯定会有自己独特的地方
So it definitely have it’s own unique way in terms of cook and taste
# 走 去尝尝吧
Let’s check it out
# 看这个搪瓷碗 这家老店的感觉就出来了
Look at this enamel bowl, it make me feel like a old restaurant
# 面馆里有个特别的现象就是
A special phenomenon in the noodle restaurant is
# 要把摞在一起的搪瓷碗 一个个地散落在锅里
The stacked enamel bowls are scattered one by one in the pot
# 这边有两口锅 这口大锅里 每次能放十多个碗
There is two pots here and there are more than ten bowls in each pot
# 碗漂浮在上面 就像小船一样
The bowl floats on the pot like a boat
# 然后就在这种飘零的状态下 里面会放上各种的佐料
There will be various condiments while it in this floating state
# 阿姨 这个碗为什么要漂在上面
Auntie, why does this bowl float on it?
# 它这个
It is
# 我讲话你懂吗
Can you understand me?
# 听得懂 听得懂
Yeah, yeah
# 因为澄一下子 它的味道就是不同
Because it tastes different
# 它澄一下的话 味道是浓的
It taste stronger after
# 不澄的话 像这一个
If you don’t, it will be like this
# 给你看一下 这个是没有澄的
I will show you, this is before
# 这一个蘸料跟这个蘸料比一下子
Compare the two
# 哦 蘸料就融合了
Oh, condiments are mixed
# 对 它的味道也不同
Yeah, it also taste different
# 这里面调料放的有猪油 酱油 这个是虾籽吗
There are lard and soy sauce in the seasoning. Is this shrimp roe?
# 是的 虾籽
yeah
# 就这几种简单的
Just these
# 6种佐料
Six condiments
# 猪油 酱油 虾籽
Lard, soy sauce, shrimp roe
# 味精 胡椒 香葱
MSG, Pepper, green onion
# 阿姨就是很热情 你不和她说话 她也会想办法和你聊天的
Auntie is very enthusiastic. If you don’t talk to her, she will find a way to talk to you.
# 到现在 聊了老半天都没有吃饭呢
We are talking for very long time until now and I haven’t eaten yet
# 我就点一个大家最常点的阳春面
I will order the Yang Chun noodles that everyone orders most often
# 然后再加一个1块5的水煮蛋
Then add 1.5 yuan boiled egg
# 这边的座位真的是很紧张
It’s hard to find a seat
# 等了好久才找的这么一个座位坐下
We just sit after that long time waiting
# 对比我以前吃的阳春面 都是把面条浸在汤里
Compared to the Yangchun noodles I had before, they all dip the noodles in the soup
# 它这碗 底料只是浅浅的一层
There’s just a very thin layer of mixed condiments at the bottom of this bowl
# 它的汤很少  胡椒味特浓郁
Just a little of soup with a strong flavor of pepper
# 就像干拌面一样
Like dry mixed noodles
# 它这个面条是又细 又顺滑 还有很大的韧劲
Its noodles are thin, smoothy and have very tender
# 味道是全在汤里的
The taste is all in the soup
# 这个虾籽酱油就是提供这种又香 又鲜的味道
This shrimp roe soy sauce provides fragrant and fresh taste
# 你看 早晨来吃饭 一般会点阳春面的人比较多
You see, there are more people ordering Yangchun noodles in the morning as their breakfast
# 逐渐到了中午 到了晚上呢 来点小馄饨的人就更多了
Gradually it’s noon, and more people come to order small wontons at the night
# 这个小馄饨 是受过汪曾祺老先生赞许的
This small wonton was praised by Mr. Wang Zengqi
# 说它家的红汤馄饨 皮薄馅多
He said its red soup wonton has a thin skin and a lot of stuffing inside
# 猪肉馅中夹有少量的竹笋 蘑菇 菌类
There are a small amount of bamboo shoots, mushrooms and fungi in the pork filling
# 吃完还会让人满口余香
After eating, it will leave full of fragrance in your mouth
# 阿姨 您的馄饨已经被写进文章里了 知道吧
Auntie, your wonton has been written in the article, right?
# 很出名了
Pretty famous
# 这个店开了很多年了吧
This restaurant has been open for many years, right
# 二十年了
About 20 years
# 哦 三十年了
Oh 30 years
# 我今年六十五了
I am sixty-five this years old
# 背景音乐：
Visionaries - 浮世绘歌舞升平
三澤康広 - つんつんけんけん
Deep East Music - Made This To Lift You
Fresh_Fallen_Snow11
# 关 注
雪 鱼  探 店